<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <title>frankhampusweslien - All content</title>
    <link href="http://frankhampusweslien.com/atom.xml" rel="self" />
    <link href="http://frankhampusweslien.com" />
    <id>http://frankhampusweslien.com/atom.xml</id>
    <author>
        <name>Frank Hampus Weslien</name>
        <email>frankhampusweslien@gmail.com</email>
    </author>
    <updated>2021-01-29T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <entry>
    <title>Life and Death</title>
    <link href="http://frankhampusweslien.com/content/blog/2021-01-29-Life-and-Death.html" />
    <id>http://frankhampusweslien.com/content/blog/2021-01-29-Life-and-Death.html</id>
    <published>2021-01-29T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2021-01-29T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Death is very simple, very clear, it happens at a particular point in time. A doctor could declare the time of death “to be between the hours of half past ten and eleven”, a vital clue as our dashing hero uncovers the murderer.</p>
<!--more-->
<p>But when it comes to the opposite of death - to life. Then time become significantly more tricky do discuss (and far more heated). Your time of birth is when you made your grand debut outside your mothers body, but you were clearly alive well before that point. Cutting you out in a c-section does not depend on the hour now does it?</p>
<p>No, life clearly started earlier. Some claim that it happens at contraception. Funny I would think, since a sperm clearly is alive and so is the egg of the mother. And if two things that already are alive fuse together then that looks, at least to me, more like a continuation then a beginning. I know that I’m slightly misrepresenting their view point. When someone says that “life begins at contraception” they probably mean something more akin to “a distinct human, with the right to life, liberty, and the pursuit happiness begins at contraception”. But again, that is me putting words in their mouth maybe that is not what they are trying to say at all? What are they trying to say?</p>
<p>Unlike death human life has no fixed point when it begins. It is gradual. A fetus grows into a human bit by bit, more and more. And life itself began ages ago. Billions of years ago.</p>]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
    <title>Vaccination is important</title>
    <link href="http://frankhampusweslien.com/content/blog/2021-01-19-Vaccination-is-important.html" />
    <id>http://frankhampusweslien.com/content/blog/2021-01-19-Vaccination-is-important.html</id>
    <published>2021-01-19T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2021-01-19T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today I got myself embroiled in a internet discussion on whether or not it is okay for people to skip the vaccination. And I’m now so riled up I have to write something down and (hopefully) avoid loosing any sleep over it.</p>
<!--more-->
<p>If you can get vaccinated, if it is safe, then it is imperative that you do. Why? Because the percentage of the population that has to be vaccinated is quite high and varies depending on the disease (95% for measles while polio only need 80%). <a href="https://www.who.int/news-room/q-a-detail/herd-immunity-lockdowns-and-covid-19#:~:text=The%20percentage%20of%20people%20who,immunity%20is%20not%20known.">[1]</a> Of course no one knows what the percentage will be for Covid-19.</p>
<p>But one thing is clear: if you don’t take the vaccine other people will have to take it in your place. Why do you get to skip while we have to take it?</p>
<p>Of course, the reason people usually cite for not taking the vaccine is their fear over any potential side effects. But since, to the best of my knowledge, taking the Covid-19 vaccine will save more lives (and lunges) than any damage side effects will cause. Maybe I’m wrong, but since every health agency on earth seem to recommend taking it I can’t imagine myself being wrong.</p>]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
    <title>Tattoos hurt (and blissful ignorance)</title>
    <link href="http://frankhampusweslien.com/content/blog/2021-01-14-Tattoos-hurt.html" />
    <id>http://frankhampusweslien.com/content/blog/2021-01-14-Tattoos-hurt.html</id>
    <published>2021-01-14T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2021-01-14T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>That tattoos hurt is perhaps no surprise to you, and it wasn’t to me either. But I had no idea what I was getting myself into. You see, this past half-year I’ve had a sleeve done on my left arm and if I had known I’m not sure I would have gone through with it. That does not mean that I regret it. In fact I do not. But it does mean I’m a bit of a wimp.</p>
<!--more-->
<p>And why shouldn’t I be wimp? It fucking hurts. “But frank”, you might ask, “how come you don’t regret it then?” Well that is simple - its over. “No pain, no gain” as you might see written across chest some jacked up dude. Ignorance is a pretty damn good way to get yourself through something that, if you would have known, never would have subject yourself to. And this principle is far wider then just tattooing. Getting my master’s degree in computer science has also been a long and arduous journey but there is only 6 months left, I’ll be damned if I don’t succeed now.</p>
<p>Often the anticipation of struggle, of pain, is worse then the actual thing. So if I can’t have anesthesia at least bless me with ignorance.</p>]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
    <title>Progress and bad paintings</title>
    <link href="http://frankhampusweslien.com/content/blog/2021-01-06-Progress.html" />
    <id>http://frankhampusweslien.com/content/blog/2021-01-06-Progress.html</id>
    <published>2021-01-06T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2021-01-06T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In my second year of university I decided I needed a new hobby. I’d tried writing but the times I could sit down and get into the flow were few and far in between. You probably know the feeling. Your past self (always that damn past self) has promised you’ll do something but when you get to it you find out your not that stoked anymore (and he can go screw himself). But you sit down, maybe in front of your computer but better would be if you’d just grab a piece of paper. Where did I put the paper again? Anyway, if you’re lucky, you get on with it. But I wasn’t getting lucky often so on whim I started painting. No particular goal in mind but I thought to myself: “man, wouldn’t it be cool if I ever do a portrait?” And you know what? I liked.</p>
<!--more-->
<p>Of course, the number of times I’ve been bored out of my mind while forcing myself to sit down and paint are more then I can count - but so are the times when I’ve forgotten what time it is. And little by little you start to get better. Not much. The progress day to day, week to week is so small… yet the progress from month to month, year to year is astounding.</p>
<p>Another thing is just how warped sense I had, and others still have, of what progress looks like. The absolute majority of all painting/drawing/sketching I do is remarkably unimpressive. There is a lot of throw away garbage you have to make before you ever get any better, and most surprisingly - the better you get the more throwaway paintings you need. Just as a runner need to run more miles, and the lifter put on another plate. As soon as what you do becomes easy you stop progressing.</p>
<p>To combat this collective narcissism that I’ll do something I’ve never done before - post one of my practice paintings.</p>
<iframe src="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1e6S-O7Xua-cZkqn1p9bPTEE_9dSCV3ZG/preview" width="640" height="480">
</iframe>
<p>I don’t know how much time I spent on it, lets say 40 minutes, a quick painting that was never meant to be seen. And even though it looks really bad I’ve found making them invaluable.</p>]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
    <title>Throne Of Might</title>
    <link href="http://frankhampusweslien.com/content/writing/poetry/theCrimsonKing/2019-05-04-ThroneOfMight.html" />
    <id>http://frankhampusweslien.com/content/writing/poetry/theCrimsonKing/2019-05-04-ThroneOfMight.html</id>
    <published>2019-05-04T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2019-05-04T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Fall from your throne, your dying seat of might,<br />
and flee this castle and its stolen tract.<br />
Be borne on the wind to ever higher height.</p>
<p>Among hot sheets of silk lies our fight.<br />
The aftermath of bloody Mars’ loving act.<br />
Fall from your throne, your dying seat of might.</p>
<p>May what sprung prove worthy above all right,<br />
A bastard demi-god who’ll have the world sacked;<br />
Be borne on the wind to ever higher height.</p>
<p>Conquering each other’s fears in the sacred rite.<br />
White stone beaten soft, beautifully cracked.<br />
Fall from your throne, your dying seat of might.</p>
<p>Brave the violent seas and tumble by its smite,<br />
Lick the warm salt, embrace your loving pact;<br />
be borne on the wind to ever higher height.</p>
<p>Fear a dove’s loving lie, its shroud of white.<br />
Wash ashore, soaked in blisters, still intact.<br />
Fall from your throne, your dying seat of might;<br />
be borne on the wind to ever higher height.</p>]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
    <title>The Grand Ball</title>
    <link href="http://frankhampusweslien.com/content/writing/poetry/theCrimsonKing/2019-05-04-TheGrandBall.html" />
    <id>http://frankhampusweslien.com/content/writing/poetry/theCrimsonKing/2019-05-04-TheGrandBall.html</id>
    <published>2019-05-04T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2019-05-04T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A full moon knocked on heaven’s door,<br />
where a slender body boiled in water,<br />
pulled to be spread on the marble floor,<br />
fair skinned, earth’s most cherished daughter.<br />
His eyes were blank, there was nothing but white.<br />
A lump hot steaming mess fixed in agony,<br />
one of the great-great souls brought back to sight,<br />
a half-hearted retort to life’s supposed monogamy.</p>
<p>“One of those days, just one of those days”<br />
as foreign carriages approached the castle<br />
where colored dots and swarms of gray<br />
spilled out to view their conquered vassal.<br />
They were greeted by a royal smile,<br />
but favored instead the crimson red,<br />
muttering for the miracle child,<br />
exclaiming, “where—where is it?”</p>
<p>Bathed in salt as if formed in ocean,<br />
on top a shell to be draped by Spring,<br />
the eternal lover’s favorite motion<br />
with copper hair curled just like the wind.<br />
The theater was laid in silverlight,<br />
and a purple haze embraced the crowd,<br />
roaring at the hint of a shadow of a sign.<br />
The rich mood dampened as the wind began to howl.</p>
<p>A stir in the clouds — an acid rain<br />
a giant’s fist’s shattering sound<br />
— a pinch of pain — trembling in awe<br />
edged to the brim — boiling in rage<br />
that’s when she threw himself on stage.</p>
<p>It’s here! It lives, it moves us!<br />
It behooves us! To take it where it groves us!<br />
My pencil, pen and rockstar muse…<br />
So obtuse, it fades — (barely used)</p>
<p>Do not ring my door; this is not my home.<br />
All parties must part their ways,<br />
and I drink my crimson red alone</p>]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
    <title>The Castle</title>
    <link href="http://frankhampusweslien.com/content/writing/poetry/theCrimsonKing/2019-05-04-TheCastle.html" />
    <id>http://frankhampusweslien.com/content/writing/poetry/theCrimsonKing/2019-05-04-TheCastle.html</id>
    <published>2019-05-04T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2019-05-04T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The spell was broken, the castle about to fall<br />
under the sun’s thousand-year-old pressure<br />
on the crimson cloaks to tear down its walls<br />
and leave the king with his only treasure.<br />
To catch him naked and then undress him,<br />
stuttering his answers to their every whim.</p>
<p>The first to fall was the gaudy chandelier,<br />
a centerpiece that stole too much attention,<br />
a display of wealth to detract from the austere<br />
condition that its shadow would never mention.<br />
And as his brilliant candles hit the floor,<br />
it cracked so deep its shadow lept from the wall.</p>
<p>He knew that future men would one day say<br />
that the crack was where it all began<br />
and never hail the sun that gave away<br />
its rays to shine on the burgeoning mountain<br />
built from the rubble of this abandoned castle,<br />
solid, with no halls to hide in.</p>
<p>Do you think of the dark side of the moon?<br />
Or the light that never kisses a body?<br />
Believing the two immortals know of bliss<br />
where all pain is shared with one another?<br />
Fear not, however close we are miles apart,<br />
two cosmonauts who just happened to cross paths.</p>]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
    <title>Ode to a Princess</title>
    <link href="http://frankhampusweslien.com/content/writing/poetry/theCrimsonKing/2019-05-04-OdetoaPrincess.html" />
    <id>http://frankhampusweslien.com/content/writing/poetry/theCrimsonKing/2019-05-04-OdetoaPrincess.html</id>
    <published>2019-05-04T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2019-05-04T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Princess, from which spring did you sprung?<br />
Yesteryear, like a flood down rolling mountains,<br />
or tomorrow bursting from a soaking tongue.<br />
You, the most oozing of youthful fountains,<br />
the prized picture in my crystal ball.<br />
Favorite niece, sweet child of mine,<br />
my youth, my home, my love, my crown!<br />
Stranger, a mist that twirls and twines,<br />
a comfortable fog who you dare not call<br />
a cloud of mind to the wonder of it all.<br />
Beloved subject, one day I’ll turn you down!</p>
<p>For I am nostalgic for the days of yore,<br />
the days when you weren’t fixed in form.<br />
In our breath, our thought, but wasn’t sure,<br />
but a distant haze, a buzzing swarm.<br />
Who came and laid the greens in a fiery show;<br />
fireflies — millions upon millions more<br />
flickering under the sun and its mistress<br />
kissing — the land blushing, shocked sore —<br />
with the red cloaks singing even though<br />
their desire is mired in the golden glow<br />
of hellfire, hellfire, heaven’s light, and hellfire.</p>
<p>Brave knight, you can not save what burned to ash;<br />
the fierce flames send shivers down your spine,<br />
a tingle, a sensation so subtle until it clash<br />
and wreaks havoc under the guise of “I feel fine”.<br />
The raging emptiness you hold inside,<br />
will it seep into a new idea, a brilliant phrase?<br />
Set things straight that didn’t need to be aligned.<br />
A curiosity exploring a warrior’s heart, a lunar phase,<br />
the white colossus of the sky that pulls the tide,<br />
in and out, day and night, the sun’s destined bride.<br />
To think that the great eight once were nine.</p>]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
    <title>Little Light</title>
    <link href="http://frankhampusweslien.com/content/writing/poetry/theCrimsonKing/2019-05-04-LittleLight.html" />
    <id>http://frankhampusweslien.com/content/writing/poetry/theCrimsonKing/2019-05-04-LittleLight.html</id>
    <published>2019-05-04T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2019-05-04T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Fickle, fickle, little light,<br />
how I beg you to guide my sight.<br />
In darkness lurks evil things,<br />
the hungry ends of blushing kings.</p>
<p>Fickle, fickle, little light,<br />
how I beg you to guide my sight.<br />
When my king is on the run,<br />
lost in darkness, lost in fun,<br />
then you bargain for my soul.<br />
Fickle, fickle, I am told.</p>
<p>Fickle, fickle, little light,<br />
How I beg you to guide my sight.</p>]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
    <title>Lady Fair</title>
    <link href="http://frankhampusweslien.com/content/writing/poetry/theCrimsonKing/2019-05-04-LadyFair.html" />
    <id>http://frankhampusweslien.com/content/writing/poetry/theCrimsonKing/2019-05-04-LadyFair.html</id>
    <published>2019-05-04T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2019-05-04T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Kindle my spirit, spirit of a dove,<br />
the rock in rock ‘n’ roll love;<br />
fair lady, lady fair,<br />
who’s wicked love turned me sane,<br />
to give such a gift so carelessly away!</p>
<p>Set a flame, flames above the tops<br />
of church bells and wedding props;<br />
lovely lady, lady love,<br />
the virgin mistress who drinks my crimson.<br />
Oh! how love turns what simply isn’t.</p>
<p>Pulling my strings, stringing me along<br />
an eternal tour through the land of wrong;<br />
prized lady, lady prizes,<br />
taken at dusk to be returned by dawn,<br />
if I could only keep you beyond the morn’!</p>]]></summary>
</entry>

</feed>
