<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <title>frankhampusweslien - All content</title>
    <link href="http://frankhampusweslien.com/atom.xml" rel="self" />
    <link href="http://frankhampusweslien.com" />
    <id>http://frankhampusweslien.com/atom.xml</id>
    <author>
        <name>Frank Hampus Weslien</name>
        <email>frankhampusweslien@gmail.com</email>
    </author>
    <updated>2019-05-04T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <entry>
    <title>Throne Of Might</title>
    <link href="http://frankhampusweslien.com/content/writing/poetry/theCrimsonKing/2019-05-04-ThroneOfMight.html" />
    <id>http://frankhampusweslien.com/content/writing/poetry/theCrimsonKing/2019-05-04-ThroneOfMight.html</id>
    <published>2019-05-04T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2019-05-04T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Fall from your throne, your dying seat of might,<br />
and flee this castle and its stolen tract.<br />
Be borne on the wind to ever higher height.</p>
<p>Among hot sheets of silk lies our fight.<br />
The aftermath of bloody Mars’ loving act.<br />
Fall from your throne, your dying seat of might.</p>
<p>May what sprung prove worthy above all right,<br />
A bastard demi-god who’ll have the world sacked;<br />
Be borne on the wind to ever higher height.</p>
<p>Conquering each other’s fears in the sacred rite.<br />
White stone beaten soft, beautifully cracked.<br />
Fall from your throne, your dying seat of might.</p>
<p>Brave the violent seas and tumble by its smite,<br />
Lick the warm salt, embrace your loving pact;<br />
be borne on the wind to ever higher height.</p>
<p>Fear a dove’s loving lie, its shroud of white.<br />
Wash ashore, soaked in blisters, still intact.<br />
Fall from your throne, your dying seat of might;<br />
be borne on the wind to ever higher height.</p>]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
    <title>The Grand Ball</title>
    <link href="http://frankhampusweslien.com/content/writing/poetry/theCrimsonKing/2019-05-04-TheGrandBall.html" />
    <id>http://frankhampusweslien.com/content/writing/poetry/theCrimsonKing/2019-05-04-TheGrandBall.html</id>
    <published>2019-05-04T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2019-05-04T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A full moon knocked on heaven’s door,<br />
where a slender body boiled in water,<br />
pulled to be spread on the marble floor,<br />
fair skinned, earth’s most cherished daughter.<br />
His eyes were blank, there was nothing but white.<br />
A lump hot steaming mess fixed in agony,<br />
one of the great-great souls brought back to sight,<br />
a half-hearted retort to life’s supposed monogamy.</p>
<p>“One of those days, just one of those days”<br />
as foreign carriages approached the castle<br />
where colored dots and swarms of gray<br />
spilled out to view their conquered vassal.<br />
They were greeted by a royal smile,<br />
but favored instead the crimson red,<br />
muttering for the miracle child,<br />
exclaiming, “where—where is it?”</p>
<p>Bathed in salt as if formed in ocean,<br />
on top a shell to be draped by Spring,<br />
the eternal lover’s favorite motion<br />
with copper hair curled just like the wind.<br />
The theater was laid in silverlight,<br />
and a purple haze embraced the crowd,<br />
roaring at the hint of a shadow of a sign.<br />
The rich mood dampened as the wind began to howl.</p>
<p>A stir in the clouds — an acid rain<br />
a giant’s fist’s shattering sound<br />
— a pinch of pain — trembling in awe<br />
edged to the brim — boiling in rage<br />
that’s when she threw himself on stage.</p>
<p>It’s here! It lives, it moves us!<br />
It behooves us! To take it where it groves us!<br />
My pencil, pen and rockstar muse…<br />
So obtuse, it fades — (barely used)</p>
<p>Do not ring my door; this is not my home.<br />
All parties must part their ways,<br />
and I drink my crimson red alone</p>]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
    <title>The Castle</title>
    <link href="http://frankhampusweslien.com/content/writing/poetry/theCrimsonKing/2019-05-04-TheCastle.html" />
    <id>http://frankhampusweslien.com/content/writing/poetry/theCrimsonKing/2019-05-04-TheCastle.html</id>
    <published>2019-05-04T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2019-05-04T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The spell was broken, the castle about to fall<br />
under the sun’s thousand-year-old pressure<br />
on the crimson cloaks to tear down its walls<br />
and leave the king with his only treasure.<br />
To catch him naked and then undress him,<br />
stuttering his answers to their every whim.</p>
<p>The first to fall was the gaudy chandelier,<br />
a centerpiece that stole too much attention,<br />
a display of wealth to detract from the austere<br />
condition that its shadow would never mention.<br />
And as his brilliant candles hit the floor,<br />
it cracked so deep its shadow lept from the wall.</p>
<p>He knew that future men would one day say<br />
that the crack was where it all began<br />
and never hail the sun that gave away<br />
its rays to shine on the burgeoning mountain<br />
built from the rubble of this abandoned castle,<br />
solid, with no halls to hide in.</p>
<p>Do you think of the dark side of the moon?<br />
Or the light that never kisses a body?<br />
Believing the two immortals know of bliss<br />
where all pain is shared with one another?<br />
Fear not, however close we are miles apart,<br />
two cosmonauts who just happened to cross paths.</p>]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
    <title>Ode to a Princess</title>
    <link href="http://frankhampusweslien.com/content/writing/poetry/theCrimsonKing/2019-05-04-OdetoaPrincess.html" />
    <id>http://frankhampusweslien.com/content/writing/poetry/theCrimsonKing/2019-05-04-OdetoaPrincess.html</id>
    <published>2019-05-04T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2019-05-04T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Princess, from which spring did you sprung?<br />
Yesteryear, like a flood down rolling mountains,<br />
or tomorrow bursting from a soaking tongue.<br />
You, the most oozing of youthful fountains,<br />
the prized picture in my crystal ball.<br />
Favorite niece, sweet child of mine,<br />
my youth, my home, my love, my crown!<br />
Stranger, a mist that twirls and twines,<br />
a comfortable fog who you dare not call<br />
a cloud of mind to the wonder of it all.<br />
Beloved subject, one day I’ll turn you down!</p>
<p>For I am nostalgic for the days of yore,<br />
the days when you weren’t fixed in form.<br />
In our breath, our thought, but wasn’t sure,<br />
but a distant haze, a buzzing swarm.<br />
Who came and laid the greens in a fiery show;<br />
fireflies — millions upon millions more<br />
flickering under the sun and its mistress<br />
kissing — the land blushing, shocked sore —<br />
with the red cloaks singing even though<br />
their desire is mired in the golden glow<br />
of hellfire, hellfire, heaven’s light, and hellfire.</p>
<p>Brave knight, you can not save what burned to ash;<br />
the fierce flames send shivers down your spine,<br />
a tingle, a sensation so subtle until it clash<br />
and wreaks havoc under the guise of “I feel fine”.<br />
The raging emptiness you hold inside,<br />
will it seep into a new idea, a brilliant phrase?<br />
Set things straight that didn’t need to be aligned.<br />
A curiosity exploring a warrior’s heart, a lunar phase,<br />
the white colossus of the sky that pulls the tide,<br />
in and out, day and night, the sun’s destined bride.<br />
To think that the great eight once were nine.</p>]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
    <title>Little Light</title>
    <link href="http://frankhampusweslien.com/content/writing/poetry/theCrimsonKing/2019-05-04-LittleLight.html" />
    <id>http://frankhampusweslien.com/content/writing/poetry/theCrimsonKing/2019-05-04-LittleLight.html</id>
    <published>2019-05-04T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2019-05-04T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Fickle, fickle, little light,<br />
how I beg you to guide my sight.<br />
In darkness lurks evil things,<br />
the hungry ends of blushing kings.</p>
<p>Fickle, fickle, little light,<br />
how I beg you to guide my sight.<br />
When my king is on the run,<br />
lost in darkness, lost in fun,<br />
then you bargain for my soul.<br />
Fickle, fickle, I am told.</p>
<p>Fickle, fickle, little light,<br />
How I beg you to guide my sight.</p>]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
    <title>Lady Fair</title>
    <link href="http://frankhampusweslien.com/content/writing/poetry/theCrimsonKing/2019-05-04-LadyFair.html" />
    <id>http://frankhampusweslien.com/content/writing/poetry/theCrimsonKing/2019-05-04-LadyFair.html</id>
    <published>2019-05-04T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2019-05-04T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Kindle my spirit, spirit of a dove,<br />
the rock in rock ‘n’ roll love;<br />
fair lady, lady fair,<br />
who’s wicked love turned me sane,<br />
to give such a gift so carelessly away!</p>
<p>Set a flame, flames above the tops<br />
of church bells and wedding props;<br />
lovely lady, lady love,<br />
the virgin mistress who drinks my crimson.<br />
Oh! how love turns what simply isn’t.</p>
<p>Pulling my strings, stringing me along<br />
an eternal tour through the land of wrong;<br />
prized lady, lady prizes,<br />
taken at dusk to be returned by dawn,<br />
if I could only keep you beyond the morn’!</p>]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
    <title>I wish I could just die; I wish I was alive</title>
    <link href="http://frankhampusweslien.com/content/writing/poetry/theCrimsonKing/2019-05-04-IWhishICouldJustDieIWishIWasAlive.html" />
    <id>http://frankhampusweslien.com/content/writing/poetry/theCrimsonKing/2019-05-04-IWhishICouldJustDieIWishIWasAlive.html</id>
    <published>2019-05-04T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2019-05-04T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>With ribbons in their mouths, the sky as their floor,<br />
that shifts and moves in see-through pinks and blues.<br />
The wonders of cosmos soon lost by the shore<br />
of oblivion, stronger than any other brew,<br />
longer lasting, the most mellow of the hues.<br />
As colored dots and swarms of grey arrive,<br />
I greet them with jokes while showing off the view.<br />
I wish I could just die; I wish I was alive.</p>
<p>Later, thinking about the doomsday-four,<br />
the quartet to orchestrate the coup<br />
on human life with all its joy and chore,<br />
and sing it out on a bittersweet adieu!<br />
That twists one’s heart as if it caught the flu.<br />
Like that stray comment that hit me in the side,<br />
and poured me on the rocks starving for advice.<br />
I wish I could just die; I wish I was alive.</p>
<p>Don’t you hear the cosmic dancers rave and play?<br />
The legends bombard every inch of floor.<br />
Can’t you feel the shock on every single day<br />
as they tap their feet chanting: “Nevermore!”<br />
Don’t you feel it slip — déjà vu, déjà vu —<br />
I write a rave review, a four out of five,<br />
and forget I ever uttered death’s sweet woo:<br />
I wish I could just die; I wish I was alive.</p>
<p>But then that eerie feeling strikes and undo<br />
all worldly joys and treats that give us drive,<br />
and for a moment only otherworldly do:<br />
I wish I could just die; I wish I was alive.</p>]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
    <title>I could not find the faults in my shapeless form</title>
    <link href="http://frankhampusweslien.com/content/writing/poetry/theCrimsonKing/2019-05-04-ICouldNotFindTheFaultsOfMyShaplessForm.html" />
    <id>http://frankhampusweslien.com/content/writing/poetry/theCrimsonKing/2019-05-04-ICouldNotFindTheFaultsOfMyShaplessForm.html</id>
    <published>2019-05-04T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2019-05-04T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I could not find the faults in my shapeless form,<br />
nor could I keep the sun and moon from kissing;<br />
eternal figures never shy to perform,<br />
while I drift not knowing what is missing.<br />
The Crimson King is laughing, “Oh, I’m yours!<br />
a portrait missing all that should be known,<br />
instead you rippled from the weight of war,<br />
and let mystique led you to be alone.<br />
See? We’ve been speaking with one tongue,<br />
both be filling empty buckets full<br />
to feel them overflow, the spring be sprung<br />
to warmth, to prince to princess, to have it pull<br />
you back into a simple twist of fate” —<br />
lacking breath I’d swallowed my own bait.</p>]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
    <title>How could it fall into your hands rosy maid?</title>
    <link href="http://frankhampusweslien.com/content/writing/poetry/theCrimsonKing/2019-05-04-HowCouldIFallIntoYourHandsRosyMaid.html" />
    <id>http://frankhampusweslien.com/content/writing/poetry/theCrimsonKing/2019-05-04-HowCouldIFallIntoYourHandsRosyMaid.html</id>
    <published>2019-05-04T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2019-05-04T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>How could it fall into your hands rosy maid?<br />
The snows of winter now in pouring spring.<br />
The Crimson King, who mourns on feathers laid,<br />
say, “Love across the lake… must art this bring?<br />
My canvas — fair — insight for all to bear;<br />
my world of ice, the beauty of winter’s gloom,<br />
now face the rising sun to sweat, to tear;<br />
its beauty lay revealed in bleeding bloom.”<br />
But let it bleed, let it cry, let the white dove die;<br />
you gnawing wraiths drink its blood<br />
the wisping winds whip its love<br />
fault in form but form is fault</p>
<p>Have autumn decay the way it was meant,<br />
while love remains our sweetest budding scent.</p>]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
    <title>All Along the Interlude</title>
    <link href="http://frankhampusweslien.com/content/writing/poetry/theCrimsonKing/2019-05-04-AllAlongTheInterlude.html" />
    <id>http://frankhampusweslien.com/content/writing/poetry/theCrimsonKing/2019-05-04-AllAlongTheInterlude.html</id>
    <published>2019-05-04T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2019-05-04T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Through mist, the rider came damp in heavy clothes.<br />
“Is this the way?”, he asked,<br />
for he wasn’t sure.<br />
“Depends,” said the gentleman.<br />
“Of course,” the charlatan.<br />
“Never,” spoke the crow.<br />
They all died in laughter, the prelude<br />
to the tale all along the interlude.</p>
<p>He mounted his bike that bleak morning<br />
when wind scuffled the leaves<br />
and rode the trees.<br />
When the levee breaks we’ll have no place.<br />
Can you hear the caw over wind and wave,<br />
awakening their deepest, most inner rage:<br />
crying floods, a burning temper. How rude —<br />
to flush us down all along the interlude.</p>
<p>The alleys crawled with sickening thoughts<br />
passing them by under flickering lights.<br />
“Thanks for tonight,”<br />
said as their hands unlocked<br />
and their (final?) eclipse was broken off.<br />
The spectacle — caught in the wrong view,<br />
by one who watch, one who pursue:<br />
eternal figures all along the interlude.</p>
<p>The past will change, blow by blow,<br />
until there is no more shelter from the storm;<br />
Where people come and go<br />
talking about comics and games for adults,<br />
the horrors of children’s toys.<br />
Letting the crow sing over wind and wave,<br />
while watchmen keep their view<br />
on the borders all along the interlude.</p>
<p>Is this his thrill? The beg, the moan.<br />
“The night doesn’t need to end here.”<br />
Hesitations unknown.<br />
And their glowing black was pulled together,<br />
by a night that seemed to last forever;<br />
A spectacle that sure looked like a crime<br />
from a distant watch in a tilted mood,<br />
like another forced entry all along the interlude.</p>
<p>Smoke curled around them. A demon? A wit?<br />
No, a hypocrite refusing to play tricks.<br />
For he was war,<br />
madness in a suit. Throwing himself at headlines,<br />
cashing in on past renown, bigger and better<br />
then any other star committing crimes,<br />
and speaks the truth — the right-wing renewed;<br />
“think of the children” all along the interlude.</p>
<p>The gentleman was the third seal that broke<br />
as he swooned and dined with mad men,<br />
lucky strikes with golden pens.<br />
“Friend, there is a lot to be gained!”<br />
Radiating blissful intent,<br />
leaving a fat tip and calling it a day,<br />
while one peddles poison to the prude and crude<br />
chanting “I broke no law!” all along the interlude.</p>
<p>— The Sirens’ Tune —<br />
The masked man strikes again!<br />
— Two scared to death<br />
Sunday morning a vigilante saved the day,<br />
or so he thought, before he was chased away<br />
by a man-made hurricane, a distraction for the crow.<br />
Please call the police if you have any clue<br />
why war rides all along the interlude.</p>
<p>The fourth had been there biding his time,<br />
day by day, the routine of your life.<br />
“A most trusted advisor.”<br />
Who you must call at once.<br />
For you find yourself amidst the worst of floods,<br />
and fear needs no more than a spark to turn hot,<br />
so you watch as the Empire subdue:<br />
“You rebel scum!” all along the interlude.</p>
<p>“My office, now!” demanded the sweaty man,<br />
the puppet in control whose flick of a switch<br />
could burn a world.<br />
While a watchman pulled off the greatest heist<br />
by staging Armageddon for the ultimate prize:<br />
to pass the day of our extinction.<br />
So let us raise a glass of crimson to our fortitude<br />
against the waves all along the interlude.</p>
<p>Bobcats growled just like the wind,<br />
while a dying fender cried out its sin.<br />
“Yes”, they swore,<br />
the gentleman, charlatan, and the crow.<br />
For no more chaos to be brought,<br />
that they leave this world, its perfect storm,<br />
while the forth was left to reap his due<br />
to judge each soul all along the interlude.</p>]]></summary>
</entry>

</feed>
